# Wasim Wadhwani

## Cybersecurity Consultant at PwC

wasim.wadhwani@pwc.com

## Summary

Wasim Wadhwani is a full time cyber security consultant with PricewaterhouseCoopers (pwc) and focuses on identity and access management solutions. He is also studying full time at Sam Houston State University for a MS in information security and assurance to further his passion and technical expertise in the cyber security field.

# Experience

### Cybersecurity Associate at PwC

August 2015 - Present (1 year 3 months)

### Student Leader - Help Desk Central at Texas A&M University

November 2012 - May 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Offer services to students and faculty of the Texas A&M University system in fields of virus/spyware removal, data recovery and backup, OS installations, hard drive and memory installations, and general tech support with mobile devices and laptops. As well as supporting accounts for faculty and students throughout the university system.

#### Setup Configuration Intern at Aon Hewitt

June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

My responsibilities include executing test plans created by the systems analysts by identifying and creating test participants within the proprietary Total Benefits Administration (TBA) software and performing calculations for expected results, documenting any defects in the system when the actual results do not meet the required criterion, writing SQL queries in DB2 SQL and retrieving data on required participant population, generating reports using the found data to be sent to the client team requesting it.

#### Teacher at The Study Center

July 2012 - August 2012 (2 months)

Instructed a class of elementary to middle school students 3D Modeling using Blender, Game Design using Multimedia Fusion 2, and Stop-Motion Film using Pinnacle Studios.

#### Co-Founder at PhoneFixNMore.com

November 2011 - June 2012 (8 months)

Maintained website

Tracked and ordered inventory

Performed diagnostics and repairs on smartphones (i.e., Apple iPhones, Android devices)

#### Teacher at The Study Center

July 2011 - August 2011 (2 months)

Instructed a class of elementary to middle school students 3D Modeling using Blender, Game Design using Multimedia Fusion 2, and Stop-Motion Film using Pinnacle Studios

## Organizations

#### **Association of IT Professionals**

August 2012 to July 2014

#### **Business IT Students (BITS)**

August 2014 to Present

#### **Creative Writers of Aggieland**

August 2011 to May 2013

#### Honors and Awards

## **Eagle Scout**

Boy Scouts of America

February 2011

Received the highest rank possible within the Boy Scouts of America organization.

#### **Presidential Service Award**

United States Federal Government

July 2010

Received the Presidential Voluntary Service Award for completing over 200 hours of community service within a span of a year.

# Volunteer Experience

#### Participant at The Big Event at Texas A&M University

March 2012 - March 2012

Providing community service to citizens of the Bryan/College Station area in miscellaneous jobs such as clearing the garden of weeds, painting the front porch and fence, and cleaning the backyard/front yard.

# Languages

**Spanish** 

(Limited working proficiency)

#### Courses

**Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Management Information Systems and Services** 

Texas A&M University

Business Programming Logic & Design	INFO 250
Database Management Systems	ISYS 315
Business Systems Analysis & Design	ISYS 320
Management Information Systems	ISYS 410
Web-Enabled Applications	ISYS 420

# Skills & Expertise

Java

**Visual Basic** 

**Microsoft Office** 

**Autodesk Software** 

**HTML** 

C++

**MySQL** 

Leadership

**Operating Systems** 

**SQL DB2** 

**Microsoft Excel** 

**CSS** 

**Game Design** 

**Microsoft Word** 

**PowerPoint** 

**Public Speaking** 

**Customer Service** 

**Teamwork** 

**SQL** 

**SailPoint** 

**Oracle Applications** 

**Identity Management** 

**Cyber-security** 

## Education

## **Sam Houston State University**

Master's Degree, Computer and Information Systems Security/Information Assurance, 2016 - 2017

#### **Texas A&M University**

Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA), Management Information Systems and Services, 2011 - 2015

# Wasim Wadhwani

Cybersecurity Consultant at PwC

wasim.wadhwani@pwc.com



Contact Wasim on LinkedIn